Inventory of the Barnes Family Papers 1797-1926, 1818-1875
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Correspondence, 1850-1869., 49 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:97-145)
  - B[alsora] Barnes, Chericoke, [Virginia], to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 20 May l859[?]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:131)
    Re: health of Aunt Judy; family activities; summer garden -strawberries and potatoes.
  - R[obert] T[omlin] Barnes, Stanly, [Virginia], to "Sister" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p. 4 pp. ALS. 20 May 1859., pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:132)
    Re: RTB has not gotten a position and sees no chances; please send pants and other summer clothing; RTB inquires about "the poor old place" and what Mr. Moncure has done with it: instructions to sod the graves.
    Also includes a letter by Peggy [Tomlin?], Stanly, [Virginia], to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p. Re: don't worry about Walker for he's fine; information about the family and everyone's health and activities.
  - R[obert] T[omlin] Barnes, Stanly, [Virginia], to "Sister" [Margaret] [W.1 [Barnes], n.p., 3 June 1859., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 2:133)
    Re: a continuation of the pants as mentioned in 20 May 1859 letter; pleased the graves have been sodded; has "the place" been sold yet?; please write to RTB.
  - [Robert] Tomlin Barnes, Chericoke, [Virginia], to "Sister" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 20. June 1859., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:134)
    Re: please write to RIB; suffering with the heat and would like another coat; wants to know how family is and how the "black people are"; hope " they have not sold my dear old home yet"; mentions grave sodding and "how much I have thought of them".
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, Montgomery, W[hite] S[ulphur] Springs, [Virginia], to "Peggy" [Margeret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 19 Aug. 1859., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:135)
    Re: particulars of mother's, [Judy] [H.] [Tomlin] [Coulter], last illness and her eventual death.
  - Fanny [?] Young, Westbrook, [?], to Margaret [W. Barnes?], n.p., 14 Nov. 1859., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:136)
    Re: glad to know your health and spirits are improving; reminiscences of younger days and activities; looking forward to your visit and bring cousin Bal[sora] [Barnes]; questions about health of family members.
  - [Robert] Tomlin Barnes, [written during his service in the Virginia army], to "Sister" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 16 Oct. 1862., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:137)
    Re: anxious to see family and to know what Walker is doing; worn out, cannot eat, and is as ragged as a buzzard; needs warm pants and new shirts; some of you please write; allowed no exercise except drilling - "Oh that it may now be over is my prayer "; sends love to everyone black and white.
  - F[anny] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 19 Jan. [l8]64., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:138)
    Re: activities during war period; information about Elega Willcox[?], her husband's running away to avoid the war, and circumstances surrounding the situation.
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 22 Jan. [l8]64., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:139)
    Re: two things FBCB forgot to tell MWB yesterday so is writing again; Peronneau was quite sick; instructions for task to be done by MWB; news of friends and relatives.
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] B[rown], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 28 Jan. [18]64., 6 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:140)
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 1 Feb. 1864., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:141)
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, n.p., to "Peggy"[Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 25 Feb. 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:142)
    Re: financial concerns
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] B[rown], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes, n.p. 4 pp. ALS. [25?] [Feb.] [1864]., pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:143)
    Re: continuation of financial concerns; status on goods and vegetables; shoes may be sent by mail.
    Also includes a letter by M[argaret] [W.] Barnes, n.p., to [postman?], n.p. Re: mailing of package to [Frances] [Bland] [Coalter] [Brown].
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] B[rown], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 16 Mar. 1864., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:144)
    Re: arrangements for future visit.
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, n.p., to [Margaret W. Barnes?], n.p., 25 Jan. 1866., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:145)
    Re: illness of Johnie [?] and Caroline and current departure plans.
  Series 4: Correspondence, 1870-1930.
- Correspondence, 1870-1930., 8 items. ALS. (Box-folder 2:146-153.)
  - B[alsora B[arnes], n.p., to Master Willie Barnes, n.p., [c. 1870]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:146)
    Re: instructions on daily living; write to Cousin Nannie for she is sick.
  - [Balsora] [Barnes], n.p., to [Master] Willie [Barnes], n.p., [c. 1870]., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:147)
    Re: confinement because of illness and lack of ability to do things for self, instructions on daily living; take care of WB's sister, Lizzy.
  - Willy [B.] Barnes, n.p. to "Aunt Lucy" Lucy [?], n.p., 18 Feb. 1870., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:148)
    Re: written over a period of five days telling of WBB's daily activities at Aunt Fanny's and at school; Thompson's birthday.
  - W[illy] B. Barnes, n.p., to "Aunt Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 18 Mar. 1870., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:149)
    Re: Aunt Fanny and Mammy Jane's health; hymn next Sunday; new books.
    Also includes a letter by F[rances] B[land] [Coalter] Brown, n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p. Re: FBCB's return home from N.Y. [?] via sleeping car; Miss Jane's great care of the boys during absence; FBCB's much improved health situation.
  - Balsora Barnes, Bremo, [Virginia], to Willie [B.] Barnes, n.p., 28 July [18]71[?]., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:150)
    Re: sorry to hear WBB had been sick; will send money for hymn book; do what Aunt Peggy and Aunt Fannie tell WBB; write and tell how Thompson is; take care of Aunt Peggy for she is always sick.
  - W[illy] B. Barnes, n.p., to "Aunt Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 5 June 1872., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:151)
    Re: visit of Mrs. Coleman and Mrs. Grinnon and arrival of Cousin Loucy Brent; Aunt Fanny gave Thompson and WBB holiday during everyone's visit; illness and departure of a dining room servant; sends love to Uncle Tomlin, Aunt Marcella[?], and Uncle Walker.
  - Fanny E. Kerr, n.p., to Willie [B.] [Barnes], n.p., 11 Apr. [l8]75., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 2:152)
    Re: religious directions to WBB.
  - Harrison T. Barnes and Miss Betty P. Cocke In Re. Estate of Lelia B. Cocke, Deceased, 11 Jan. 1926., 1 page. T. Doc. (Box-folder 2:153)
    Re: disapproval of the partitioning of Bremo and desire to have the personal property appraised by an expert.
  Series 5: Correspondence, n.d.
- Correspondence, n.d., 57 items. ALS. (Box-folder 3:154-210)
  - Nancy [?], Chericoke, [Virginia], to [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton, Culpepper County, Virginia, 30 Jan. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:154)
    Re: departure of guests; birth of a daughter to Mrs. B[raxton]; getting Armistead ready for school up in Caroline; Walker's illness; love to family members.
    Also includes a note by Lucy [?], Chericoke, [Virginia], to [Margaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Jeffersonton, Culpepper County, [Virginia]. Re: "Cousin Lucy" sends love to all and particularly to Peg.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to Beverly Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:155)
    Re: a scolding from BB about Beverly's not taking proper care of his health.
  - [Balsora] [Barnes], n.p., to George Barnes, n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:156)
    Re: pantaloons are finished; please write; how is GB's Mama's health?
    Also includes a letter by [Balsora] [Barnes], n.p., to "Peg" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p. Re: why has MWB not written?; questions about fowls and Peg's studies; love to MWB's Mama, Papa, and brother.
  - Balsora Barnes, n.p., to "Peg" M[argaret] W. Barnes, Green-field, [Virginia], n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:157)
    Re: MWB's trip home; George's arrival.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 24 June n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:158)
    Re: Lucy's illness; arrangements for BB's trip home; hopelessness of Jack Bryan's illness and surrounding circumstances; general family news.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to "Peggy" M[argaret] W. Barnes, Greenfield, Culpeper [County], [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:159)
    Re: wedding and plans concerning travel and visit.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to "Peggy" M[argaret] W. Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], n.d., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:160)
    Re: soreness in BB's hands and difficulties encountered.
    Also includes a note by B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to George [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: why has GB forgotten BB?; declaration of love for George.
    Also includes a note by B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to Bev[erly] [Barnes],Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: why has BB not written?
    Also includes a note by Bal[sora] [Barnes], n.p., to Tom[lin] [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: you are a fine boy.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], n.d., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:161)
    Re: exchange of presents; BB hopes that the boys can stay for the winter for BB was beginning to teach them to write.
    Also includes a letter by Lucy H. Barnes, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: Willy's children and their education; health of family members.
    Also includes a letter by F[rances] C. B[arnes], n.p., to Lucy [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: sewing and quinces.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], Chatham, [Virginia], to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], 30 May n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:162)
    Re: St. George's serious illness; will send clothes for the boys; can't see at all.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpeper [County], [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:163)
    Re: Peggy's attending school near BB, Peggy's failure to arrive yet, and the value of an education for Peggy; sen d the boys to BB and BB will prepare them for a large school; Lucy's wedding; illness of St. George.
    Also includes a letter by L[ucy] M: H. B[arnes], n.p., to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, Culpeper [County], [Virginia]. Re: family affairs.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:164)
    Re: Willy's illness; clothes for the boys.
    Also includes a letter by [Balsora] [Barnes], n.p., to Lucy [Barnes?], n.p. Re: the house is not done.
  - B[alsora] Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia],to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, care of Dr. Braxton, Old Church P[ost] Office, Hanover County, Virginia, [?] Oct. n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:165)
    Re: Beverly [Barnes] - ".. .all old maids can lecture on the instruction of children to a painful extent t o married ladies, Beverly still proves a dutiful teachable child.. ."; information about the activities of all family members.
  - [Balsora] [Barnes], n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] [Williamson] [B.] [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. AL. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:166)
    Re: BB's love for people and how feelings often "discompose" you; Margaret [Tomlin's?] feelings on how NWBB should come up here and not gander off with Miss S[?] to New York; cousin Coulter has lost her bridge and others are down in the area; James. N. is a devoted admirer of Fanny's.
  - Balsora Barnes, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:167)
    Re: have you and George any work for BB; Cousin Lucy's health is improving; pray often for NWBB's happiness and have loved NWBB more than any being on earth with the exception of two; NWBB's future conduct toward Margaret [Tomlin?] and interpretive statement of Margaret's feeling toward NWBB.
  - Balsora Barnes, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:168)
    Re: requests items to be purchased for BB, Judy, Lucy, Aunt Amy; "Margaret [Tomlin?] sends her love to George and yourself.
  - Balsora Barnes, Chericoke, [Virginia], to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], 17 May n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:169)
    Re: BB has not sent shirts because of illness; news of Margaret [Tomlin?] and her journeys; BB requests items to be purchased.
    Also includes a letter by Margaret W. Tomlin, Chericoke, [Virginia], to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia]. Re: requests items to be purchased.
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to "Willy" N[ewman] W[illiamson] [B.] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], 11 Apr. n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:170)
    Re: "stips"? sent for Peg, Lucy, you two and the boys; write to us.
    Also includes a note by [Lucy?] [?], n.p., to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia].
  - B[alsora] B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to "My dear B" [N.?] B. Barnes, Culpeper C[ounty], Virginia, 27 June n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:171)
    Re: pantaloons and clothing; horse that was left; Mama wants to visit Greenfield in July & Mama's health; the garden; please write, we have been mortified at your silence.
    Also includes a letter by B[alsora] B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to "My dear M" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], Culpeper C[oun]ty, Virginia Re: BB sends MWTB tea towels with [Bret's?] pantaloons coat; hope MWTB's health is improved; love to the "dear little children" and to Willy.
  - F[rances] C. B[arnes], Chericoke, [Virginia], to "My dear Brother" New[man] [Williamson] [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], 24 Feb. n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:172)
    Re: "Margaret has a new beau but I do not think you need to dread him as a rival"; the Ball in Richmond; has NWBB heard from home?
  - L[ucy?] H.[?] B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], [?] Sept. n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:173)
    Re: NWBB should take better care of his health; religious remarks; health news of family members; Bet is too busy to write.
  - Lucy M. B[arnes], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] Barnes, n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:174)
    Re: LMB is glad MWB is attending to MWB's books and being a good child obedient to your parents and brothers; LMB is going to see MWB's Grand Mamma.
  - L[ucy] M. B[arnes], Falmouth, [Virginia], to Margaret [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 1 page. ALS. (Box-folder 3:175)
    Re: George made his appearance last night; LMB fears that Willy is offended; love to all.
  - L[ucy] N. H.[?] B[arnes], n.p., to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], n.d., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:176)
    Re: LMHB saw Willy last night; what is the matter with Peg and Tomlin?; Judy, the children and St. George [Coulter] are all well; LMHB sent some things to all of you by Mr. Georges[?] Charles.
    Also includes a note by L[ucy?] [M.] [H.?] B[arnes], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: the want of paper compels me to write to MWB and your mother on the same paper; be a good child and take care of yourself; read your bible and get a portion of it everyday.
  - Lucy M. H.[?] B[arnes], n.p., to Margaret W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:177)
    Re: LMHB has just returned from Chatham; want to know' if MWTB and family is dead or alive; LMHB is sending Willy's other shirt; why does Peggy not write to LMHB since LMHB has spent so much time instructing her?; all are well except Papa; Bal[sora] and Fanny are at St. George's and Cousin Coulter dines with them today; love to all.
  - L[ucy?] M. H.[?] Barnes, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "My very dear Brother" [Newman] Williamson B. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], between 20-30 Aug. n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:178)
    Re: NWBB should not be so low spirited for "surely a young man never had greater cause for a thankful heart than you," LMHB fear that if NWBB continues to be unhappy when he has so much that "our kind heavenly Father should visit them with some heavy, but just punishment"; Mama and Aunt Short have left us on a visit to Mrs. Allison; news of Bal[sora], Margaret, Judy, and Mama; the times are dull; do not be so tardy in answering letters; the girls all write with LMHB in best love to you and George.
    Also includes a note by M[argaret] W. Tomlin, Falmouth, [Virginia], to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson B. Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia]. Re: goods requested.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., to "Mama" M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], 31 May n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:179)
    Re: delighted to hear you and father are well; Uncle Coalter's illness and Aunt Judy's subsequent unhappiness; have George write and tell MWB about MWB's hen, chickens, and garden.
    Also includes a letter by B[alsora] B[arnes], n.p., to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia]. Re: pleased you two invalids are improving; glad to know Willy's prospect for corn is good.
  - M[argaret] W. Barnes, St. Georges [home], [Virginia], to "Mamma" M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Greenfield, [Virginia], 13 Aug. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:180)
    Re: MWB is homesick and desires to come home; MWB is concerned about Papa's illness and brother Bev's; news about Uncle Coalter and Aunt Judy, Aunt Bal[sora], and Aunt Lucy; love to Papa, Aunt Margaret, Uncle B. and MWB's little brothers.
    Also includes a letter by Balsora Barnes, St. Georges [home], [Virginia], to M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, n.p. Re: family situations.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], n.p., to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 14 Mar. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:181)
    Re: Aunt Mary and Cousin Nannie went up to see Col. Carrington; Uncle [?] got MWTB's letter about Tomlin; Beverly seemed very happy when he was here last; Aunt Margaret Tomlin; news of activities and health of various family members; MWB's activities and travel plans; MWB sends love to all in family.
  - M[argaret] W. Barnes, Lower Bremo, [Virginia]., to "Mama" M[argaret] W. [Tomlin] Barnes, Falmouth, Stafford County, Virginia, 12 Oct. n.y., 3 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:182)
    Re: Fanny Braxton has been confined to her bed with violent toothache and pain in her face; arrangements for trip to Richmond; cold weather has arrived; Mrs. Bryan and the Bryan girls.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:183)
    Re: instructions for staying well; the ice house repairs; family activities.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], Chericoke, [Virginia],. to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 27 May n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:184)
    Re: instructions to "Mama" for staying well; mention of family visits and activities; illnesses of friends and family.
    Also includes a letter by M[argaret] W. B[arnes], Chericoke, [Virginia], to Bal[sora] [Barnes], n.p. Re: Cousin Maria's distressful situation; MWB's quilt.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Stanley, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 16 Jan. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:185)
    Re: Aunt Judy's illness and circumstances surrounding the seriousness of the illness; MWB's concern over MWTB's poor health; family visits and activities.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., to "Mama" [Margaret] 1W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 5 May n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:186)
    Re: relates MWB's accident with knife and subsequent problems with the near loss of MWB's finger; activities and health news of family members.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Stanley, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 30 Jan. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:187)
    Re: snow storm and its effects for all friends and relatives;' Beverley's trip to Wheeling; Jack and his report of activities at Chericoke.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], Stanley, [Virginia], to "Ma" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 4 Feb. n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:188)
    Re: Hybla house burned down and Armistead was only able to save a few things; Mattie [?] has caught one of the first beaux in the state - Mr. Wilcox Brown; some of you write to MWB.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], Stanley, [Virginia], to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 9 Apr. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:189)
    Re: health news of family members; MWB scolds MWTB about what MWTB writes in her letters asks MWTB to be more careful about who she talks about.
  - M[argaret] [W.] B[arnes], n.p., to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., 5[?] Sept. n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:190)
    Re: news of family activities and trips including visits to the Springs; mentions news of many family members.
  - M[argaret] W. B[arnes], n.p., to [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:191)
    Re: family news; Uncle Walker's new baby, John Walker.
  - M[argaret] W. Barnes, n.p., to Tomlin [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:192)
    Re: Aunt Lucy has given a favorable account of TB and Walker [in your studies]; family ventures; Cousins Coulter and Janet are both sick; George looks better than MWB's seen him in a long time.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], Old Church, Virginia, to "Peggy" Margaret W. Barnes, Pine Wood, near Falmouth, Virginia, 28 May n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:193)
    Re: cotton sent.
    Also includes a letter from [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., to "Mama" [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p. Re: a thank you note.
  - [Margaret] [W.] [Tomlin] [Barnes], n.p., to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:194)
    Re: recipe and brief news of NWTB's activities.
  - Mary T. Braxton, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Richmond, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:195)
    Re: instructions for repair of hat, request for knitting needles not sent as requested, and a list of desired goods to be purchased for MTB.
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, Red [Level?] Springs, [Virginia], to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 1 Sept. n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:196)
    Re: FBCB would have been glad for MWB to join FBCB here; Cousin William thinks that FBCB has had a nervous disorder; the treatments FBCB has enjoyed and FBCB is sure MWB's health requires it too; arrangements for MWB's stay in Bedford.
  - F[rances] B[land] C[oalter] Brown, Chericoke, [Virginia], to "Peggy" [Margaret] [W.] [Barnes], n.p., 5 Ap[ril] n.y., 4 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:197)
    Re: Ma's illness and FBCB's attempts to go and nurse her; arrival at "Stanley" and report of Ma's health; would like MWB to come - FBCB will nurse MWB too; family news; invitation for a visit to Bedford.
  - Betsey George, Culpeper C[our]t H[o]u[se], [Virginia], to Balsora Barnes, Falmouth, Virginia, [?] Aug. n.y., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:198)
    Re: Elizabeth and BG have feeble health; Elizabeth went to the warm springs and came home because she became nervous there; report of Elizabeth, Will an d John Walker's families.
  - Judy L. Sydnor, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Hanover Town, [Virginia], n.d., 2 pages. ALS. (Box-folder 3:199)
    Re: have sent NWBB a pair of socks.
    Also includes a letter by J[udy] H. Tomlin, n.p., to "Willy" [Newman] Williamson [B.] Barnes, Hanover Town, [Virginia]. Re: JHT apologizes for bad behavior on Tuesday evening.